## **Pooja Sudev**

☑ ipoojaprakash@gmail.com 📞 8589012052 🔮 Ahmedabad, Gujarat

# 13 Jun 1993

in www.linkedin.com/in/poojasudev

#### **PROFILE**

Motivated and responsible Data Analyst with five years of working experience including 3.8 years of experience in highly accurate collection, analysis, and interpretation of large datasets. My career objective is to secure a financial professional position in a reputable organization to utilize and enrich my data analysis, financial knowledge, and skill.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Data Analyst,** S & P Global

Aug 2019 - present Ahmedabad

- Responsible for the interpretation, analysis and updating of financial and nonfinancial data on publicly traded companies in an accurate manner to the database using technical and financial knowledge.
- Dealing with annual reports, interim reports, and press releases of the companies that are trading in different stock exchanges across the globe.
- Content collection of financial statements like Income statements, Balance Sheets, Cash Flow statements and Per Share Statements of the companies and making necessary classifications which is a key input for deriving the final products.
- · Maintaining quality standards by providing necessary updates & contributing as a team member towards necessary enhancement in the process and tool.
- Analyzing the financial statements and notes to financial statements to gather information such as Employee Stock Benefit Schemes, Options & Warrants etc.
- Analyze team quality by identifying errors through offline & online check logics.
- Keeping an up-to-date knowledge of content sets and building industry knowledge by understanding industry trends and reporting standards.
- Cross-trained in six other processes.
- Mentorship to new employees.
- Active member of the Employee Engagement Committee (EEC).

## **Accomplishments:**

- Certified Lean Facilitator for successfully implementing a lean project resulting in savings of 161 hours.
- Recognized as **Fundamentals Champ** for being the best performer.
- Received Zero Defect Award for embracing "First Time Right" culture.
- · Most Versatile Team Award for smart sourcing.
- **Dynamic Team** award for the most versatile team.
- Successfully completed mentorship of the cross-trained member.

## **Relationship Manager,** HDFC Bank Ltd.

- Jul 2018 Apr 2019 | Kochi
- Monitored customer requirement, identified prospective opportunities and assisted in increasing revenue.
- · Created and maintained pipelines of business banking sales opportunities.
- Supported bank's strong relationship banking culture through ongoing customer contact, quality customer service and product knowledge.
- Managed all product inquiries for customers by providing direct & indirect solutions and successfully handled all complaints without any escalations.

#### **Accomplishments:**

- Honored with the "Rising Star" award.
- Successfully managed a portfolio of over 1300 customers with book size crossing 18
   Cr.
- Exceeded income goal by 105% for March'19 as per interim reports.

## **Intern - Credit Department,**

Ian 2018 - Mar 2018 | New Delhi

Dewan Housing Finance Corporation Ltd (DHFL)

- · Verification of all documents before login.
- Login the loan file and generate a unique ID.
- Generating all other documents i.e CIBIL, tracker in DHFL.
- Preparation of PD report.
- · Making cases in the format given by the company and sending them for approval.

## **HR Coordinator,** Moksha Designs Pvt. Ltd

Aug 2015 – Jun 2016 | New Delhi

- Employee onboarding, documentation, and database maintenance.
- Maintaining and tracking attendance & leave for all levels of employees.
- · Monthly preparation of MIS report, ESIC, and EPF report and letters.
- Planning and execution of employee engagement programs.
- Liaison with the bank for activation of corporate salary account.
- Assisting in payroll processing.
- · Handling employee grievances and exit interviews.

## **Accomplishments:**

• Honored with "Queen of the Hill" award for being the best employee.

## **PROJECTS**

## Lean Project - Same SOLR rule is appearing twice in found combo box

2022

This project helped **reduce the waste of over processing** which lead to **savings of 161 hours**.

# **Project Report, Dewan Housing Finance Corporation Ltd.**

2018

Conducted a comparative analysis of financial performance of Dewan Housing Finance Corporation Ltd with selected Housing Finance companies based on "CAMEL" approach.

## Organisation Study, Akay Flavours and Aromatics Pvt. Ltd.

Conducted a detailed organizational study of the various departments of the organization.

### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCES

**Volunteered for S&P Global India Essential Impact December** 

**Volunteered for Corporate Responsibility - Notebook Upcycling** 

Event Head – Product Launch Event – Tantra 2k17 – National Level Management Fest

Coordinator in Orientation programme for new students in MACFAST College, Tiruvalla

Coordinator for Job Fair conducted in MACFAST College, Tiruvalla

**Volunteered for National Literacy Mission** 

## **CERTIFICATES**

Certified Lean Facilitator

NISM Certification Series V-A: Mutual Fund Distributors Examination

## **EDUCATION**

MBA in Finance and Human Resource, MACFAST, Mahatma Gandhi University

2018 | Tiruvalla

B.Com (Hons), SOL, University of Delhi

2014 | New Delhi

## **SKILLS**

Quick Learner | Multi-task | Analytical Skills | Decision making
Leadership Skills | Strong attention to detail
Good Written and Verbal Communication | Computer Skills | Persistence
Flexible | Investigative nature | Project Management skills
Positive attitude | Financial Data Collection Application
Individual Contributor | Team player